Ashutosh Singh

Al Engineer, ashutoshsingh0223@github.io

I have 3+ years of experience working with startups in India where I worked on NLP based products. I am currently doing applied research at Fraunhofer Institute with tasks such as Image Segmentation and Multi-Modal Signal Processing, Keypoint Detection etc. using Deep Learning, trying to apply these technologies to industry projects. I also co-founded a company in India and created a video streaming services development platform from scratch.



ashutosh.singh.de@gmail.com



+4917670784103



ashutoshsingh0223@github.io



linkedin.com/in/ashutosh-singh-0b2694137



github.com/ashutoshsingh0223



stackoverflow.com/users/11154 976/ashutosh-singh

SKILLS

Python

AWS

Deep Learning

Computer Vision

NLP

Docker

Langchain/LLMs

Web Development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Associate Fraunhofer IGD

12/2022 - Bis jetzt Rostock, Germany

Special achievements/responsibility

- Development and Analysis of Fish measurement pipeline using python, pytorch and torchvision.
- Pipeline consists of keypoint detection, inverse relative depth estimation and relative to absolute depth regression.
- Tools: mlflow, python, numpy, matplotlib, pytorch, git.

Research Assistant Fraunhofer IIS

11/2021 - 11/2022 Erlangen, Germany

Special achievements/responsibility

- Studying and analyzing latest developments in efficient architectures of Image Segmentation, like MobileNet, ShuffleNet, ESPNet etc.
- Developed U-Net like architectures based on more efficient and sparse architectures like Depth-Wise separable and grouped convolutions.
- Master Thesis Multimodal Signal Processing and Data Fusion methods for emotion detection on datasets like MAHNOB-HCI using end-to-end Deep Learning.
- □ Tools: weights & biases, python, pytorch, matplotlib, git.

Machine Learning EngineerJio Haptik Technologies Limited

01/2019 - 01/2021 Mumbai, India

Special achievements/responsibility

- Developed conversational AI modules like small talk, named entity recognition.
- □ I also worked on Freebase data to build entity embeddings for tasks like domain classification.
- □ Worked on a side project for paraphrase generation using variational autoencoders.
- As an attempt towards data driven development, I developed a data analysis tool for bot analysts to remove bugs in training data.
- □ Tools: Python, pytorch, numpy, matplotlib, django, mongoDB, JIRA, git, Amazon Web Services, Docker, docker-compose, rabbit-mq, celery.

LANGUAGES

English

Muttersprache oder zweisprachig

Hind

Muttersprache oder zweisprachig

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computational Engineering University of Erlangen-Nuremberg

11/2020 - 11/2022

courses

- Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning
- Image & Video Multi-dimensional Signal Processing, Image & Video Compression
- Software Development Project(10 ECTS)
- Machine Learning in Signal Processing
- Algorithms in Numerical Linear Algebra

Erlangen, Germany

Lugano, Switzerland

INTERESTS

Sketching

Anime

Sci-fi Movies

Working Out

Calisthenics

Master of Science, Computational Science

Università della Svizzera italiana

11/2020 - 11/2022

Lehrveranstaltungen

 Advanced Topics in ML, Introduction to Bayesian Computing High Performance Computing